You know, when we talk about the ancestors who came before us and those whose lives were taken,
so often folks are speaking of their ancestral wisdom in terms of the knowledge that they had.
But the wisdom that we can also gain is from the naivete that they had.
Now, as I watch a black man escort this racist fool who stopped through Minnesota and got his nuts handed to him,
I say to myself, have we not learned yet?
Did we not learn from Martin Luther King Jr.'s regretting integrating his people into the burning house?
Did we not learn that there is no moral suasion?
Did we not learn when Stokely Carmichael said, in order to fight an enemy with nonviolence, they have to have a conscience?
Did we not learn when the late Assata Shakur said, nobody in the world, nobody in history has ever gotten their freedom
by appealing to the moral code of those oppressing them?
I want to set y'all free.
Your goodness, your kindness is not measured by how much you put yourself in danger to protect those who would see you slain.
We don't need more martyrs, and we also don't need more folks allowing for the oppressor to think that we are here to protect them.
The great Patrice Lumumba was assassinated on this day in 1960,
and he genuinely believed that there would be freedom for the people of the Democratic Republic of Congo
because he believed that the oppressors that they were negotiating with
were operating under a human code of consciousness and conduct.
You know, the rub is, it's not that they didn't see us as human.
It's that they don't see themselves as human.
So just know that we will never smite out our enemy until we understand not only how they see us,
but how they see themselves.
I think you'll find, sir, that there will come a time when black people wake up
and become intellectually independent enough to think for themselves.
As other humans are intellectually independent enough to think for themselves,
then the black man will think like a black man.
And he will feel for other black people.
And this new thinking and feeling will cause black people to stick together.